# **Lynn Amsbury**

Email: Lynn8542@gmail.com | Phone: 303-940-0332 | Highlands Ranch, CO, 80130 LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/lynnamsbury/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/lynnamsbury/</a> | Github: <a href="https://github.com/LynnAmsbury/">https://github.com/LynnAmsbury/</a> | Website: <a href="https://lynnamsbury.github.io/">https://github.com/LynnAmsbury</a>

#### JUNIOR WEB DEVELOPER

Motivated, hardworking Full-stack web developer with a medical background who is enthusiastic and willing to learn. Superior knowledge of medicine and the sciences. Experience with managing tight deadlines, processing large amounts of information promptly, and demonstrating attention to detail.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap 4, the command line, git, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, Applications: GitHub, Firebase, Moment.js, Node.js, MySQL, Express, Heroku, MongoDB, React.js

#### **PROJECTS**

Journey's Shelter Management Application | <a href="https://journey-shelter-manager.herokuapp.com/">https://journey-shelter-manager.herokuapp.com/</a> | https://mahume.github.io/Trip-Over-This/

# **Co-Developer**

- This application offers business management for animal shelters via animal and donation databases. Users may add and view animal records as well as both material and monetary donations.
- Developed using React.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, Express, AuthO, the pdfkit npm package, React-Bootstrap, and Bootswatch.

Mongo Mongoose Scraper | <a href="https://github.com/LynnAmsbury/mongo-mongoose-scraper">https://mongo-mongoose-scraper</a> | <a href="https://mongo-mongoose-scraper">https://mongo-mongoose-scraper</a>. | <a href="https://mongo-m

- This full-stack app scrapes and displays headlines from Westword.com. Users may also save and comment on those articles. All data is stored in a Mongo database.
- Developed using Bootstrap/Bootswatch, Handlebars, jQuery, Cheerio, Express, MongoDB, and Mongoose

The Great Stress Escape | <a href="https://github.com/LynnAmsbury/the-great-stress-escape">https://github.com/LynnAmsbury/the-great-stress-escape</a> | <a href="https://thegreatstressescape.herokuapp.com/">https://thegreatstressescape.herokuapp.com/</a>

# **Co-Developer**

- The Great Stress Escape is a full-stack application intended for immediate relief of stress using calming images, inspirational quotes, and soothing sounds.
- Developed using Bootstrap, Handlebars, Express, Node.js, MySQL, and Sequelize

Liri-Bot | https://github.com/LynnAmsbury/liri-bot Developer

- Liri-bot is a command line interface (CLI) app created in Node.js that takes in user input (performers, songs, and movie titles) as parameters and returns information about each of those inputs.
- Developer using Node.js, axios, dotenv, moment, and node-spotify-api

# GifTastic Project | https://github.com/LynnAmsbury/GifTastic-Project | https://lynnamsbury.github.io/GifTastic-Project/ Developer

- This project is an on-click gif population page using gifs from GIPHY.
- Developed using HTML, JavaScript, jQuery, and the GIPHY API.

#### **EDUCATION**

## University of Denver, Denver, Colorado

2018-2019

An intensive 24-week long boot camp dedicated to designing and building web applications. Skills learned consisted of HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, JQuery, Firebase, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handlebars.js, & React.js.

## University of Colorado School of Medicine, Denver, Colorado

**Doctor of Medicine** 

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Medical Writer 2015-2017

Aegis Creative Communications

Checked the FDA for newly released medications and provided clients with summaries of the history, development timeline, mechanism of action, and therapeutic significance of any medications that could conflict with their products. Delivered summaries to the client within 8 hours including coordination time with the project medical editor and the project manager, demonstrating excellent deadline management skills and the ability to manage large volumes of information in a short amount of time.

Academic Editor 2015-2016

Enago

Provided editing services to medical and scientific professionals who were not native English speakers who wanted to have their work published in English-language journals, demonstrating very close attention to detail.

# **ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE**

#### AllMed Healthcare Management, Remote

Physician Clinical Reviewer

CareCore National, LLC, Remote

**Medical Director** 

# Rocky Mountain Urgent Care, Denver metropolitan area

Physician